{
    "id": "30faf8e29ae74467a572ea015f645f9e",
    "title": "Future Tenses Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "87f275d6e80a4cc1ac4b9c33ac1324ef",
            "title": "Talking About Future",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I …………… you if you say that word again.",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to express our intentions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "am hitting",
                        "will be hitting",
                        "will hit"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I think our team …………",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to predict the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will win",
                        "would win",
                        "will be winning"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………….. I help you with the housework?",
                    "description": "We use shall in offers of help.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Will",
                        "Would",
                        "Shall"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This time tomorrow I ……………. a discussion with my boss.",
                    "description": "We use the future continuous to say that an activity will be in progress at a particular time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will have",
                        "will be having",
                        "am having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "By next Christmas we ……………….. in this city for twenty-five years.",
                    "description": "We use the future perfect to say that something will be completed by a certain time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have lived",
                        "will have lived",
                        "will be living"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………….. home late tonight.",
                    "description": "To predict future events we usually use will / shall + infinitive without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "will be",
                        "would be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She …………….. before too long.",
                    "description": "To predict future events we usually use will / shall + infinitive without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will arrive",
                        "is arriving",
                        "would arrive",
                        "would be arriving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will phone you when I …………… time.",
                    "description": "In many subordinate clauses we use present tenses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will have",
                        "would have",
                        "will be having",
                        "have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will discuss your situation with my boss when I …………. him tomorrow.",
                    "description": "In many subordinate clauses we use present tenses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "meet",
                        "will meet",
                        "would meet"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will follow you wherever you ………….",
                    "description": "In many subordinate clauses we use present tenses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "are going",
                        "will go",
                        "go"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can take anything I ……………",
                    "description": "In many subordinate clauses we use present tenses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will find",
                        "am finding",
                        "find"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ……………. upset when she finds out what you have done.",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to predict the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is upset",
                        "would be",
                        "will be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}